<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tamarindo Guide</string>

    <!-- Category name for beaches [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_beaches">Beaches</string>

    <!-- Category name for the dining [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_dining">Dining</string>

    <!-- Category name for activities [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_activities">Activity</string>

    <!-- Category name sights [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_sights">Sights</string>

    <!-- Activity titles -->
    <!-- Activity title for ATV Tours [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_atv">ATV Tours</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Fishing [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_fishing">Fishing</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Kayaking [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_kayaking">Kayaking</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Paddle Boarding [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_paddleBoarding">Paddle Boarding</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Rafting [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_rafting">Rafting</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Sailing [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_sailing">Sailing</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Surfing [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_surfing">Surfing</string>

    <!-- Activity title for Zipline [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="activity_zipline">Zipline</string>

    <!-- Activity descriptions -->
    <!-- Activity description for ATV Tours [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_atv">ATV tours in Tamarindo get you off the beaten path and
        out into the tropical forest. Rain or shine, these tours cater to the adventurous traveler
        not content with the sights to be seen only on oft-traveled roads. Tamarindo ATV tours take
        you into the bush, along the beach, under the canopy of the forest and across rivers and
        streams otherwise inaccessible by normal means.</string>

    <!-- Activity description for Sailing [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_sailing">Take to the high seas on a sailing cruise aboard one
        of the many catamarans and schooners for hire. Most tours are all inclusive with an open bar
        and snacks or meals. Day cruises will sail to nearby Costa Rican beaches, some of which are
        only accessible by ocean. One of the best ways to enjoy one of local glorious sunsets is
        aboard a sail vessel, with the wind in your hair, a drink in your hand and nothing but the
        sound of the ocean in your ears.</string>

    <!-- Activity description for Fishing [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_fishing">Sportfishing for rooster fish, tuna, wahoo, dorado
        and catch-and-release billfish in Tamarindo is excellent year round and the close proximity
        to the continental shelf makes for a very short run time. Most restaurants will prepare the
        anglers catch of the day.</string>

    <!-- Activity description for Kayaking [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_kayaking">Taking a Kayak Tour to the Tamarindo Estuary offers
        an adventure through a wildlife filled nature setting.  The estuary sits between Tamarindo
        Beach and Playa Grande. A tour provides an opportunity to view some Costa Rican animals
        including crocodiles, iguanas, monkeys, and a variety of bird species. Another option is
        along the coast to one of the nearby islands.  Bring your snorkling gear to add another
        element to the adventure.</string>

    <!-- Activity description for Paddle Boarding [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_paddleBoarding">Practiced by Hawaiians for centuries,
        Stand-Up Paddle Boarding (SUP) was rediscovered about ten years ago by surfers in Hawaii.
        The sport is correctly named as enthusiasts not only surf on the oversized boards, but also
        glide (paddle along the coast), explore the estuaries of Costa Rica, fish off of them or
        simply use them as a great workout. The technique can be mastered in about an hour, which
        makes SUP a great vacation activity.  The board has a leash that attaches to the ankle or
        knee of the stand up paddle boarder, turning the board into your own personal flotation
        device. Many people enjoy the perspective that SUP provides and often say it feels like
        walking on water. It is a great activity to do as a group as there is plenty of time to
        converse while SUP. Be sure to use sunscreen and consider a rash guard or other clothing as
        the stand up paddle boarder spends nearly all of his time out of the water.</string>

    <!-- Activity description for Rafting [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_rafting">Costa Rica is known for its amazing network of
        rivers and streams, and rafting tours offer great floats on Class 2 and 3 rivers. Many great
        outfitters offer rafting tours with English speaking guides and professional equipment to
        provide incredible and unforgettable white water experience.</string>

    <!-- Activity description for Surfing [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_surfing">Tamarindo has been known as the ultimate surf town
        for many years. The iconic movie Endless Summer 2 put Tamarindo on the map as an
        international surfing destination. It truly is a surfing paradise, drawing surfers from
        around the globe. One of the greatest attractions is the diversity and consistency of the
        surf, not to mention the year round balmy water temperatures. There are surf spots for all
        levels, and Tamarindo is ranked as one of the Top 10 beaches in the world for learning to
        surf.  There are many surf schools, as well as surf camps. For miles to both the north and
        the south of Tamarindo, world class surfing can be found at numerous uncrowded beaches.
    </string>

    <!-- Activity description for Zipline [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="activity_description_zipline">A challenge best left for all the Survivor and Fear
        Factor wannabes, this Costa Rican zip line canopy tour leaves no time for hanging about.
        Zoom through the tropical tree tops on one of the many zipline tours within a short distance
        from Tamarindo. The region is filled with many zip line parks. Proving Tamarindo is much
        more than just white sandy beaches and world-class surf spots, take half a day away from the
        waves and sign up for one of the most exciting adventures in Costa Rica, the zip-line
        capitol.</string>

    <!-- Sights titles -->
    <!-- Sights title for Llanos de Cortez Waterfall [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_llanos">Llanos de Cortez Waterfall</string>

    <!-- Sights title for Monkey Park [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_monkeyPark">Monkey Park</string>

    <!-- Sights title for Palo Verde National Park [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_paloVerde">Palo Verde National Park</string>

    <!-- Sights title for Rincon de La Vieja [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_rinconVieja">Rincon de La Vieja</string>

    <!-- Sights title for Rio Celeste [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_rioCeleste">Rio Celeste</string>

    <!-- Sights title for Rio Perdido [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_rioPerdido">Rio Perdido</string>

    <!-- Sights title for Turtle Nesting [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="sights_turtles">Turtle Nesting</string>

    <!-- Sights descriptions -->
    <!-- Sights description for Llanos de Cortez Waterfall [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_llanos">The Llanos de Cortez Waterfall is less than a two-hour
        drive from Tamarindo. Once you reach the bottom of the trail, you’ll see why Llanos de
        Cortez is considered to be one of Costa Rica’s most beautiful waterfalls. The falls are wide
        and wispy, with streams of water tumbling along the mossy rocks. Rocky cliffs are visible
        through the transparent cascade. To add to the grandeur, thick forest surrounds the falls
        with many birds and monkeys bellowing from the trees. At the base of the falls is a nice
        pool, good for swimming or wading, and there is a sandy area to just hang out and relax. If
        you want to explore, walk along the banks of the river to see frogs and tadpoles, small
        fish, and the Jesus Christ Lizard (it can actually run across the surface of the water).
        Behind the falling waterfall is shallow cave to explore.</string>

    <!-- Sights description for Monkey Park [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_monkeyPark">About a 20 minute drive north of Tamarindo is
        Monkey Park. Not ot be confused with being a zoo, as all of the animals have come from being
        rescued. Monkey Park is a non-profit foundation that has made itself available to the
        indigenous wildlife of Costa Rica in order to provide a safe and experienced environment for
        the local wildlife’s rehabilitation and release needs. Its staff and program have been
        expertly tailored to benefit a balanced ecology by providing educational opportunities for
        visitors. Simply put, animals at Monkey Park are set up to allow the opportunity to behave
        as they would in the wild.</string>

    <!-- Sights description for Palo Verde National Park [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_paloVerde">Palo Verde National Park has a uniquely dichotomous
        character.  It’s simultaneously a spectacular wetlands and one of the best examples of
        tropical dry forests remaining anywhere in the world.  Birds are the biggest attraction at
        the park. Many of the resident tropical bird species nest on Isla de Pajaros in the Río
        Tempisque. This island in the river provides a safe nesting place for Egrets, Spoonbills,
        Storks, Herons, and many others to breed. Variegated Squirrels, Howler Monkeys, Coatis,
        Capuchin Monkeys, Deer and Peccaries can also be seen in the park.  Note – the river is not
        a good place to swim, as this is where you will see crocodiles sunbathing along the banks of
        the river.</string>

    <!-- Sights description for Rincon de la Vieja [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_rinconVieja">Rincon de la Vieja is about a 90 minute drive from
        Tamarindo, and is located about 30 minutes northwest of Liberia. It is one of 6 active
        volcanos in Costa Rica. There are 9 eruptive craters along its ridge, so if you are an avid
        hiker, you will have to check in with the ranger station before heading out to explore the
        many miles of trails. On clear day from the top you will be able to see the Pacific and the
        Gulf of Mexico. There are canopy tours, horseback riding, river rafting and ATV tours in the
        available in the immediate area.  Also, be sure to bring your swimsuit, so you can enjoy one
        of the many local hot springs. </string>

    <!-- Sights description for Rio Celeste [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_rioCeleste">Located about two hours north east of Tamarindo is
        the Tenorio and Miravalles volcanic area.  Although both volcanoes are considered dormant,
        there is still a great deal of geologic activity within this locale: geysers shoot water
        into the air and hot springs bubble up from below ground. Even better, and much more famous,
        is the Río Celeste, a river whose blue-tinted waters are the result of a chemical mixture
        produced by the Tenorio Volcano. Exploration of the Tenorio Volcano National Park is
        rewarding, as it hosts rivers and waterfalls amidst a dense forest setting. These forests
        provide a unique habitat for animals such as ocelots and jaguars and can be toured on either
        foot or horseback.</string>

    <!-- Sights description for Rio Perdido [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_rioPerdido">Rio Perdido is actually a resort about 2 hours from
        Tamarindo.  It offers a unique experience for a day trip or a vacation stay. Once within the
        600-acre private reserve, you are drawn into a deep and beautiful canyon where a thermo-
        mineral river literally emanates from the steep rock walls. You can soak in one of the
        dozens of natural thermal pools along a mile of thermal river, or you can opt for a long
        therapeutic massage in our world-class spa. Other options are the unique canyon zip line
        adventure, giving a birds eye view of the Rio Blanco Canyon.</string>

    <!-- Sights description for Turtle Nesting [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="sights_description_turtles">Just north of Tamarindo is Playa Grande, home to the
        2nd largest nesting site for Leatherback sea turtles in the entire world. The Leatherback
        sea turtle can grow into one of the largest reptiles in the world and is seen here for
        months at a time at Las Baulas. Not only is turtle watching unmatched elsewhere, Playa
        Grande also features a turtle research facility, with researches that will take guests to
        view turtle nesting at night. Laying and hatching seasons begin in October and end in
        March.</string>

    <!-- Beach titles -->
    <!-- Beach title for Playa Avellanas [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_avellanas">Playa Avellanas</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Playa Brasilito [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_brasilito">Playa Brasilito</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Playa Conchal [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_conchal">Playa Conchal</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Playa Danta [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_danta">Playa Danta</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Playa Flamingo [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_flamingo">Playa Flamingo</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Playa Grande [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_grande">Playa Grande</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Playa Langosta [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_langosta">Playa Langosta</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Bahia de los Piratas [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_bahia">Bahia de los Piratas</string>

    <!-- Beach title for Tamarindo [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="beach_tamarindo">Tamarindo</string>

    <!-- Beach descriptions -->
    <!-- Beach description for Playa Avellanas [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_avellanas">Avellanas is one of the most beautiful beaches in
        the Tamarindo area. There is nothing but pristine beach wilderness. The long ribbon of beach
        reaches north to Playa Langosta and south to Playa Negra. Some stretches are rocky and
        feature tide pools. Other parts have powdery white coral sand and turquoise water. One of
        the biggest attractions to Playa Avellanas are some of the best surf spots in Costa Rica,
        drawing surfers from all over the world.</string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Brasilito [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_brasilito">This dark sand beach is situated right next to
        Playa Conchal. There is an awesome little island down toward the north end that strong
        swimmers can paddle out to. Lots of locals use this beach, so it is the perfect place to
        grab a beer and meet people.</string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Conchal [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_conchal">Named for the millions of crushed seashells that
        wash upon its shores, Playa Conchal is a shimmering beauty of pink sand and turquoise sea.
        This idyllic stretch of beach is set in a curved bay overlooking the Catalina Islands, known
        as a great spot for snorkeling and diving. On a good day the water is so clear you can see
        straight to the bottom even in very deep water. As you walk along the beach southward toward
        the estuary, the sand gets whiter and finer (like powdered sugar). Also, there is an open
        air market fronting the beach, where visitors can purchase local handicrafts.</string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Danta [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_danta">Danta and its sister beach, Dantita ("Little Danta")
        are gorgeous, light-sand beaches just outside of the luxurious Las Catalinas development.
        There is a little shop called "Pura Vida Ride" where you can rent paddleboards and mountain
        bikes.</string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Flamingo [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_flamingo">This white-sand, crescent-shaped beach is nothing
        short of dreamy. Sometimes you can spot little rays surfing the gentle waves in the bay.
        The water is beautiful here, often shining in multiple shades of turquoise, green and
        blue. </string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Grande [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_grande">Another great surf spot.  The beach of Playa Grande is
        long strip of fine, pale sand backed by a coastal vegetation. The beach is mostly uncrowded.
        When there you must be careful to avoid stepping on the soft-sanded upper part of the beach,
        as you might destroy turtle egg layings. Playa Grande belongs to the National Park Las
        Baulas and is home to an important nesting site of leatherback sea turtles. After sundown no
        visitors are allowed on the beach, unless they are accompanied by a park guide. </string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Langosta [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_langosta">Situated directly south of Playa Tamarindo, Playa
        Langosta is home to some of the best surfing in the area. white-sand dunes and the scenic
        estuary of the Rio San Francisco. Around low tide you can cross the river by wading through
        waist-high water at the outer edge of the river mouth. Playa Langosta is known as a great
        spot to relax and feel the sand between your toes. However, sometimes there are strong
        currents here, so be careful if you have little kids</string>

    <!-- Beach description for Bahia de los Piratas [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_bahia">This known locally as the "secret beach". This
        postcard-perfect beach is fantastic for snorkeling, and not many vacationers know about it.
        Drive like you are going to Playa Grande, but take a right instead of a left at the town of
        Matapalo. Follow the signs and when in doubt ask someone for directions. </string>

    <!-- Beach description for Playa Tamarindo [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="beaches_description_tamarindo">Playa Tamarindo has been known as the ultimate surf
        stop in Costa Rica for many years, and there are surf spots for all levels. With a long
        stretch of sand, warm ocean, many tide pools and consistent waves, it is a water lovers
        paradise. It is located at about a 50 minute drive from the international airport in
        Liberia, and considered to be the regional central hub for beach activities. </string>

    <!-- Dining titles -->
    <!-- Dining title for Black Stallion Cafe and Surf Saloon [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_black">Black Stallion Cafe and Surf Saloon</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Dragonfly Bar and Grill [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_dragon">Dragonfly Bar and Grill</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Green Papaya [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_green">Green Papaya</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Longboards BBQ [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_longboards">Longboards BBQ</string>

    <!-- Dining title for La Baula [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_baula">La Baula</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Latitude Blue [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_latitude">Latitude Blue</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Nogui's [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_noguis">Noguis</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Seasons by Shlomy [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_shlomy">Seasons by Shlomy</string>

    <!-- Dining title for Sprout [CHAR LIMIT=30] -->
    <string name="dining_sprout">Sprout</string>

    <!-- Dining descriptions -->
    <!-- Dining description for Black Stallion Cafe & Surf Saloon [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_black">Self-described as Costa Rican cowboy saloon with a
        surfer twist. Offering a private and exclusive rustic ranch style evening.  Specializes in
        small groups, such as special events for families and friends. The BBQ is outside in a shack
        under the stars, where people relax in the cafe or saloon, which have a unique rustic wood
        design. </string>

    <!-- Dining description for Dragonfly Bar & Grill [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_dragon">Dragonfly is beloved for its refined menu and its
        upscale tiki-bar atmosphere. The open-air dining room has twinkling lights and lanterns,
        with a subtle dragonfly motif throughout. The eclectic menu leans Asian, but fuses elements
        from around the world. Go for the Buddha Bowl filled with goodness or the fiery Thai beef
        served on glass noodles. Desserts are also divine.</string>

    <!-- Dining description for Green Papaya [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_green">Swing on up to the bar for a breakfast burrito or pull
        up a tree-stump stool to sample the terrific tacos at this fantastic new addition. The mahi
        mahi tacos are perfection in a tortilla, while non-meat eaters will appreciate the multiple
        veggie options. You will go loco for the Coco Loco dessert. Everything is funky, fresh and
        friendly.</string>

    <!-- Dining description for Longboards BBQ [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_longboards">An American-style BBQ joint and expat favorite,
        with pulled pork, ribs and beef brisket. Belly up to the surfboard-shaped tables and grind
        some proper BBQ. The bartenders also mix some potent drinks and (often) show US sports on
        the TVs.  A great place to catch the big game while being on vacation, and enjoy some
        great BBQ.</string>

    <!-- Dining description for La Baula [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_baula">The best pizza in Tamarindo by some accounts. This
        casual open-air restaurant has real wood-fired pizzas with a wide variety of toppings, as
        well as pastas and other Italian fare. It’s also one of the most family-friendly restaurants
        in town, with a playground to keep the kids entertained. However; with the open-air, woodsy
        setting you will probably need some insect repellent.</string>

    <!-- Dining description for Latitude Blue [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_latitude">Sitting directly on the beach, Latitude Blue provides
        a large gourmet menu and unique entertainment.  Enjoy the ocean breeze and gorgeous sunset,
        while enjoying delicious food and listening to live music.</string>

    <!-- Dining description for Nogui's [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_noguis">This friendly fish shack has one of the best beachfront
        locations in town. Its a perfect perch for a sunset drink or seafood dinner. Theres nothing
        special going on with the food – just basic preparations served in paradise. This is a great
        place to stop for a cold beverage and a great burger when returning from an ocean adventure.
        </string>

    <!-- Dining description for Seasons by Shlomy [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_shlomy">Seasons by Shlomy offers poolside dining with a
        Mediterranean fusion menu. Don’t leave town without eating here. Israeli chef Shlomy offers
        a short list of carefully selected and perfectly prepared dishes. Depending on the
        availability of ingredients, you might start with grilled octopus or a lobster-leek terrine.
        Follow up with seared tuna in a honey chili marinade or filet mignon in red wine sauce.
        Perfection on a plate. The understated yet elegant open-air restaurant has indoor seating
        and romantic poolside tables. Reservations are recommended.</string>

    <!-- Dining description for Sprout [CHAR LIMIT=NONE] -->
    <string name="dining_description_sprout">Delicious lunch and dinner made only from fresh,
        organic, and locally sustainable ingredients. A friendly family environment; right across
        from the beach (directly across from Witches Rock Surf Camp). Sprout exists to provide the
        community of Tamarindo and the surrounding towns with a restaurant option that is healthy,
        fresh, and sustainable yet prepared at the highest of culinary standards.</string>

</resources>

